

As a software engineer and full stack web developer, I am experienced in contributing to team success through the art of software development and dedication to my craft. Rooted in a passion for learning, I have built a strong skill set which includes 5+ years' experience in applying Object-Oriented and Functional programming techniques.

2 (734)969–5442

in/in/luke-belinc

₼/luke-belinc

@belinc@tuta.io

Experience

Software Engineer

- **Associate** > Built and regularly maintained internal software tools for the Experience Management Product Support organization
- Verint Systems > Automated workflows to create efficiency of scale while also reducing manual errors
- 02/2022-08/2022 > Delivered continuous QoL updates to legacy software and systems
 - ➤ Built and deployed single page web applications via AWS EC2
 - > Tasked with providing all necessary CLI training to colleagues
 - > Coordinated multiple projects from initial planning through deployment
 - > Acted as admin for 20+ mission critical PowerBI waterfall reports and data gateways
 - > Utilized Agile software development approach with each project
 - > Doubled 2022 annual release target goal by August

- **Systems** > Built software extensions for the GEOS-Chem and WRF-Chem modeling systems
- **Programmer** > Drew up comprehensive bug reports to identify pain points and provided solutions
- WSU-Huang Lab Authored scripts to interpret and generate maps from atmospheric data models 3/2020–10/2020 > Automated software execution and data collection using Bash, cron, and Slurm via
 - > Implemented GNU Make to automate software builds
 - > Held regular CLI training sessions with research students

Skill Set

Languages C, C++, C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Go, Bash, Haskell, CommonLisp, FORTRAN, Ruby

Frameworks/Libraries Angular, React, Express, Jasmine, POSIX, pandas, Tkinter, NumPy, NLTK, Qt, .NET, ASP.NET, jQuery, Rails

Tools Unix shells (zsh, sh, Bash), GNU coreutils, Vim, Slurm, cron, PowerShell, Git, Node.js, ⊮∏-X, AWS (S3, EC2, Lambda), Database Managament Systems (PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle Database), Jira, Confluence

Methodologies Agile, CI/CD, Behavior- and Test-driven development

Projects/Hackathons

Advent of Code Various code challanges completed using Haskell, C++, and Python

DHack Designed health monitoring app using AWS Lambda, JavaScript and React Native. Won 2nd place overall and 1st place for the FitBit challenge.

MHacks 8 Designed set of dev tools for remote maintainance of GM Console software. Used C, JavaScript, and Wayland to manipulate system and interact with screen remotely.

Chinese Character Dictionary Designed a simple character meaning and stroke order dictionary and thesaurus using Python, PostgreSQL, and Qt

Mock Terminal POSIX shell built in C

Education

Wayne State University B.S. in Computer Science Detroit, MI 2016-2021

References

Matthew Crawford Director, Product Support (248) 595 - 5635 **in**LinkedIn

Matthew Heinrich Engineer, DevOps (646)385-5524 **in**LinkedIn